# kinto behr

# data scientist

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a data scientist and statistician with expertise in R and a keen interest in process automation, package development, and applied statistics. Although I am most comfortable in R, I have varying degrees of experience with a number of other languages from SQL (fluent), through Python, LaTeX, HTML/CSS and JavaScript (intermediate), to C++ (beginner).

Outside of work, I am an active contributor to the open source software community, having developed or made large contributions to a number of R packages. More information and an expanded resume are available at https://kinto-b.github.io

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# Statistician

Social Research Centre | 2022 - Present

I am currently situated in the statistical methods team, where I am involved in broadly two kinds of work. On the one hand, I carry out statistical procedures like survey weighting, bias assessment, and non-response analysis. On the other hand, I am responsible for streamlining and automating data processing, analysis and reporting pipelines. Some of the things I have worked on in this latter capacity are

- Redesigning the SQL database and associated workflows that underpin the Life in Australia study
- Automating and standardising our survey weighting procedure
- Developing a Shiny application with SQL-based user-management for multi-client reporting of small area estimates

#### **Data Scientist**

Social Research Centre | 2020 - 2022

I was the lead data scientist on the SES, which approaches hundreds of thousands of higher education students each year. In this capacity, I was responsible for maintaining the data infrustructure throughout the full length of the pipeline from sample collection and validation, through fieldwork operations and data processing, to report production.

In addition, I made key contributions to the in-house R package architecture and Shiny application suite. In particular, I

- Authored and/or maintained the majority of in-house packages
- Trained other data scientists in R package development, helping them to become maintainers in their own right
- Developed a number of complex Shiny applications which became core to projects across the business, including one which won a company-wide competition

#### Team Lead

Sidekicker | 2018 - 2020

I was in charge of the community operations team, which was responsible for ensuring that the application marketplace was running smoothly. Alongside managing 15+ casual staff, I performed data analysis using SQL and Python, and automated core processes to save 100hrs of labour-time per month.

### **EDUCATION**

# Graduate Diploma in Science (Advanced)

University of Melbourne | 2021 - 2023

- pecialising in statistics and stochastic processes.
- Maintaining a 4.0 GPA with a current rounded average of 87%.

#### **Bachelor of Arts (Honours)**

University of Melbourne | 2021 - Present

- Graduated top of my class with a GPA of 4.0 and a rounded average of 87%. (Transcript available upon request).
- Wrote a thesis in philosophy on the theory of knowledge.

# **Bachelor of Arts and Bachelor of Science**

Monash University | 2013 - 2017

- Achieved a GPA of 3.93 with a rounded average of 87%. (Transcript available upon request).
- Majored in physics and philosophy; minored in mathematics and Japanese language.
- Received numerous academic awards including the Dean's List Fellowship Award and five best in unit awards (for achieving top marks across various physics classes).

# **SELECTED HONOURS**

- 2019 Hastie Prize in Philosophy, the University of Melbourne
- 2016 Peter J. Lloyd Prize in Theoretical Physics, Monash University